## **MATTHEW ADENYO**

Address: AP19 Tufohene Nyame Street (WR-758-5163), Beposo – Shama, Western Region, Ghana

Email: adenyomatthew@gmail.com Tel: (+233) 24 789 8793

**LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/matth-adenyo **Portfolio:** https://matth-adenyo.github.io/

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

A skilled data analyst, teacher, researcher and leader with experience in teaching, researching, leadership, collecting, organizing, interpreting and disseminating various types of statistical figures. Energetic presenter and confident communicator with the ability to circulate information in a way that is clear, efficient and beneficial for all end users. Creative in finding solutions to problems and determining modifications for optimal use of organizational data.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Mentorness – Gujarat, IN

Apr 2024 - May 2024

## Data Analyst Intern [Remote]

- Performed data cleaning, analysis and visualization to support business decision making.
- Developed an interactive dashboard for in-depth insights to understand contributing factors and trends in aviation incidents using Power BI.

# Cognifyz Technologies - Nagpur, IN

Mar 2024 - Apr 2024

### Data Science Intern [Remote]

- Assisted in developing machine learning models to predict customer behaviour.
- Conducted exploratory data analysis to identify key trends and insights.
- Implemented data pre-processing techniques to prepare data for analysis.

# **Learners Platform** (<a href="https://www.learnersplatform.com/">https://www.learnersplatform.com/</a>) - Accra, GH

Mar 2023 - Mar 2024

### Mathematics Tutor [Full-Time]

An e-learning platform, known for its interactive and innovative learning support for Nursing Training Students, High School Students and Basic School Students across Africa.

- Provided Mathematics tutorials to Senior High School and Junior High School Students.
- Provided solutions to Senior High School and Junior High School Mathematics past questions.

# University of Mines and Technology (UMaT) - Tarkwa, GH

Nov 2021 - Oct 2022

## Teaching/Research Assistant [Full-Time]

- Assisted lecturers with research works and presentations.
- Assisted lecturers with classroom instructions, exams, record keeping and other miscellaneous projects.
- Tutored and mentored undergraduate students in Mathematical Programming, Linear Algebra, Calculus and Numerical Methods & Scientific Computing.
- Conducted tutorials and review sections.
- Marked assignments and tests.

## Shama District Assembly (SDA) - Shama, GH

Jun-Aug 2018

## Revenue Officer (Internship) [Full-Time]

- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Assisted in field monitoring and inspection.
- Prepared permits for individuals and organizations.
- Assessed buildings for property rate bills and revenue collection.

# Nata Academy Preparatory School - Beposo, GH

## Mathematics, Science & ICT Tutor [Full-Time]

- Taught all classes of the school level curriculum from JHS 1 3 Mathematics, Integrated Science and ICT.
- Administered feedback to students using positive reinforcement techniques to encourage and build confidence.
- Participated in professional development activities to improve tutorial skills and grow cultural competence and reflection skills.
- Participated in training classes to improve tutoring practices and learn new tutoring techniques.
- Implemented listening and questioning strategies to diagnose student needs and monitor progress.
- Prepared and delivered regular lessons, prepared workshops for staff, and conducted tutorial sessions and classes where necessary.

### **PROJECTS**

# • Game Analysis: Decoding Gaming Behaviour | SQL

Conducted an in-depth analysis of gaming behaviour using SQL, extracting and analysing large datasets to uncover player trends and patterns. Used advanced analytical techniques to decode player engagement and performance metrics.

### Restaurant Data Analysis | R

Analysed a restaurant dataset to explore insights and build predictive models. Cleaned, processed and analysed the datasets to identify key trends in customer behaviour, menu preferences and most common price range. Implemented statistical models and visualizations to provide actionable insights for optimizing menu offerings, pricing strategies, and operational efficiency. Build four different predictive models to predict rating of restaurants and compare their performance.

### • Pizza Sales Analysis | Power BI

Executed end-to-end analysis of pizza sales data using Power BI, showcasing proficiency in data extraction, transformation and visualization and employing advanced data visualization techniques to identify key trends and insights such as top and bottom performers by revenue, quantity and orders and customer's favourite pizza type and size.

#### **EDUCATION**

EDUCATION	
University of Mines and Technology (UMaT) - Tarkwa, GH BSc Mathematics (Second Class Upper)	Nov 2021
Ghana Sec/Tech School (G.S.T.S) -Takoradi, GH WASSCE (General Science Option)	
AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS	
Internship Completion Certificate, Cognifyz Technologies	Apr 2024

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS		
Internship Completion Certificate, Cognifyz Technologies	Apr 2024	
• Statement of Accomplishment, Data Analyst in SQL – DataCamp [Credential]	Jan 2024	
• Statement of Accomplishment, Data Scientist with R – DataCamp [Credential]	Oct 2023	
• Certified Associate Data Scientist – DataCamp [Credential]	Sep 2023	
UNESCO-India-Africa Hackathon Finalist	Nov 2022	
• Certificate of Completion, Power BI Fundamentals – Festman Learning Hub	Sep 2022	
• Certificate of Completion, Introduction to Data Science in Python: Coursera [Credential]	Feb 2022	
• Certificate of Completion, Data Scientist's Toolbox: Coursera [Credential]	Nov 2021	
• IBM Cognitive Class, Data Science Orientation: Coursera [Credential]	Nov 2021	
• IBM Cognitive Class, Data Science Methodology: Coursera [Credential]	Dec 2021	
• IBM Cognitive Class, Tools for Data Science: Coursera [Credential]	Dec 2021	

### **ACTIVITIES & AFFILIATIONS**

•	Association of Mathematics Students (Uni. of Mines and Tech.), President	Nov 2020 – Jul 2021
•	Ghana Methodist Students' Union (Uni. of Mines and Tech.), President	Apr 2019 – Jul 2021

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Computer Skills: Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Power BI).
- **Personal Skills:** Excellent Interactive and Interpersonal Skills, Leadership Skills, Teaching, Research, Attention to Details, Critical thinking and analytical skills, Problem- Solving skills, Communication, Teamwork.
- **Technical Skills:** Latex, R, Python, SQL, Graphic Design (Adobe Photoshop), Data Science/Analysis, Data Visualization, etc

### REFERENCE/REFEREES

# **Dr Henry Otoo**

Head, Mechanical Engineering Department University of Mines and Technology (UMaT), Tarkwa hotoo@umat.edu.gh | +233 54 141 4406

# Dr Kofi Agyarko

Lecturer, Department of Mathematical Sciences University of Mines and Technology (UMaT), Tarkwa kagyarko@umat.edu.gh | +233 24 617 3533